<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Jeremy C. Simon</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©2019</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cross-Group Interaction</title>
      <link>/project/internal-projects/cross-race-interaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/internal-projects/cross-race-interaction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Status: nearing the end of data collection!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re studying whether interactions between strangers differ as a function of race. By comparing pairs of White participants with White/Black pairs we can investigate the effects of interracial interactions on a number of measures of understanding and empathy. Our dependent variables include action coordination, empathic accuracy, and dehumanization, plus neural measures including mu suppression and neural synchrony.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demographic Ignorance</title>
      <link>/project/internal-projects/demographic-ignorance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/internal-projects/demographic-ignorance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Status: under review!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This line of work tests whether changing Americans&amp;rsquo; perceptions of their country&amp;rsquo;s diversity affects their attitudes toward minorities. As you can see above, we&amp;rsquo;ve been surprised to find that making people think minorities make up a larger portion of the population actually decreases their implicit (and explicit) prejudice. It also decreases their conservatism.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpersonal Dehumanization</title>
      <link>/project/internal-projects/interpersonal-dehumanization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/internal-projects/interpersonal-dehumanization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Status: planning follow-up. Look for my poster at SPSP 2020!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve run two studies testing whether we can manipulate perceptions of humanity with simple trait descriptions. We&amp;rsquo;ve found that our manipulation succeeds in making our targets less human, and that this predicts less attribution of pain (above), greater punishment, and more painful medical decision-making. However, we&amp;rsquo;ve also been manipulating targets&amp;rsquo; race, but that has no effect. We are attempting to disentangle whether individual and group sources of dehumanization override one another or combine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Categorization</title>
      <link>/project/internal-projects/multiple-categorization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/internal-projects/multiple-categorization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Status: in prep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been using Representational Similarity Analysis to test whether we can decde the group identity of multiply categorized targets. Participants viewed videos of minimal in-group and out-group members who were also racial in-group or out-group members. We&amp;rsquo;ve found that we can easily decode either racial or minimal group identity, suggesting that both categories are simultaneous represented. We have yet to find a representational structure combining both categories.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
